Will Yang

Full-Stack Developer

willyangzzz@gmail.com | New Zealand Resident | linkedin.com/Will-Yang | github.com/WillYangZzz

ABOUT ME

Kia ora! I am a full-stack developer with a diverse background in Education. I have participated in a variety of projects during my time in Dev Academy Aotearoa, which have equipped me with modern web development stacks such as React and NodeJS, as well as an ability to quickly pick up with new technologies. With 10+ years of experience in the education sector, I've always been a problem solver, adept at recognizing challenges and devising efficient, targeted solutions. This journey has honed my communication skills, empathy, and collaboration abilities to work in a team. I'm excited about the endless possibilities in the tech world and I'm eager to be part of this innovation and creativity.

EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer | Dev Academy Aotearoa

July 2023 - December 2023

- This was a life-changing 17-week, 800+ hours full-immersion software development bootcamp that
 closely represents working in a modern development team. The course taught me a modern
 development stack with a strong emphasis on human skills, teamwork, self-awareness and how to learn
 on the fly.
- Each week, we were given hands-on challenges to do on my own or construct web applications by pair programming.
- The program strongly emphasized human skills, empathy, and well-being. Every Friday, we would join
 forces and build applications in teams of four. This gave me opportunities to exercise giving and
 receiving growth feedback and working in teams using agile methodology.
- Collaborating with a four-member team, I led the design and development of a comprehensive travel planning web application, leveraging React and JavaScript technologies. Our robust full-stack project integrated Auth0 for seamless user authentication, ensuring data security and user privacy. The platform streamlined itinerary creation, offering users a dynamic interface to plan, organize, and customize their travel experiences efficiently. I acted as the Product Owner, which involved making decisions and prioritising work in order to ensure the product reached its maximum value. We utilised agile methodologies such as stand-ups to unblock each other, retrospectives to reflect, discuss and improve, and a kanban to track and prioritise tasks.

Software Developer Internship| MVP Studio

March 2023 - Present

MVP STUDIO (New Zealand) is a talent & tech startup incubator and tech product development company. It also provides tech-skill and soft-skill training mentored internships. While at MVP STUDIO, I have gained experience working as a full-stack web developer using upfront technologies.

Technologies: ASP.NET Core MVC, React, Ant design, NPM, Git, MongoDB, Entity Framework, LINQ, Microsoft SQL Server, Semantic UI, AJAX, and Axios.

Web Developer Remote Internship | TimeTrove England

Nov 2022 - March 2023

TimeTrove is a new, tech-for-good and interactive digital platform that helps people of all ages sort and treasure their most meaningful memories.

During my web development internship, I immersed myself in real-world coding challenges, refining my skills in HTML, CSS, and JavaScript. Under mentor guidance, I contributed to various projects, learning to create

responsive layouts and implement functionalities. Collaborating with the team, I gained hands-on experience in debugging, version control with Git, and working within Agile methodologies. Engaging in code reviews and troubleshooting bolstered my understanding of best practices. This internship offered a rich learning environment, enabling me to expand my knowledge, tackle practical issues, and emerge with a deeper understanding of the intricacies involved in professional web development.

Qualified Early Childhood Teacher | Childcare centers in NewZealand

Mar 2018 to Feb 2023

BestStart is one of the biggest Early Childhood organisations in New Zealand.

EDUCATION

NZQA Level 6 Certificate in Applied Software Development | Dev Academy Aotearoa

April 2022 - July 2022

Graduate Diploma in Teaching | New Zealand Tertiary College

March 2018 - April 2019

TECHNICAL SKILLS

JavaScript | React.js | HTML | CSS | Git | SQLite | REST APIs | Python | auth0 | asp.net | Node.js | Express.js

INTERESTS

As a tennis enthusiast, I frequently play with my club friends and aspire to attend the four major Grand Slams worldwide. Music and reading is an integral part of my life, providing a source of inspiration and rejuvenation that helps me stay motivated and focused in my work.

REFERENCES AVAILABLE UPON REQUEST